POONAM PATEL

Geospatial Specialist | GIS Specialist

Email: pvp.poonam@gmail.com Mobile: +65-87532218

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/poonam-patel-gis-specialist/

(MOE Scholarship bond for 3years)

SUMMARY

GIS Specialist, having a Master's in Geomatics with 4+ years of experience enables me to meet the diverse requirements of the converging industry. I am currently seeking a challenging opportunity through which I can grow my knowledge and implement my learnt skills, thus effectively contributing to the company. An eye for detail, creative thinking and delivering results efficiently are qualities I bring with me.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Singapore Land Authority, Singapore

11/2019 -11/2020

Senior Geospatial Specialist

- Processing the GIS data for OneMap routing
- Managing Geospatial data using ArcMap, QGIS, ArcGIS Pro
- Creating PL/SQL scripts (cycling, Driving, Walking) to process data for routing
- Web application development and design using HTML/CSS / JavaScript / Leaflet/OpenLayers /Node.js /PostgreSQL
- Create raster tiles and vector tiles for base map using Geospatial data.
- Perform research to obtain and expand existing datasets and technologies.
- Gather and report on GIS data and determine how data sets are best utilized through GIS.

Quantum Inventions, Singapore

03/2019 -07/2019

Intern-GIS Developer

- · Extracting data from data sources like OpenStreetMap and openly licensed government data
- Developing & designing methodology
- Generation of a geospatial ETL pipeline for data and Validation of GIS map data
- · Development of pedestrian routing for Singapore using Django-Python, Postgres, Leaflet

ENVIRONMENTAL MANAGEMENT CENTRE LLP, Mumbai, India

01/2017 -06/2018

GIS Specialist

- Developing GIS outputs for projects such as Geodatabase creation, Conducting LULC Classification and Watershed Analysis using SWAT, Arc Hydro, Geo-referencing of the satellite images and toposheets.
- Supported project workflows, data preparation, Geo data processing, data storage, GIS modeling and analysis, development of technical, professional project reports
- Managing Geospatial data using ArcMap, QGIS, ArcGIS Pro
- Create maps and graphs, using GIS software and data collection equipment.
- Generation of base shape files through digitization, Database creation, Production of various thematic maps for reports and presentation, Generations of Reports.
- Performing Shadow Flicker and Noise Modelling Formulating impact scenarios. Spatiotemporal analysis and creating modelling outputs for various themes of the project.

Image Analyst

- Measurement of quality of expansion in urban areas using high resolution imagery.
- Satellite Image processing, Spatiotemporal analysis, Land Use categorization, Arterial Road mapping using Satellite data and other sources.
- Design, create, update, and maintain geographic data and maps
- Data quality assessment on raster and vector data formats.

CEPT University, Ahmedabad, India

01/2015 - 05/2015

Teaching Associate

- Developed course work Structure for subject GIS for landscape architecture.
- Delivered practical sessions and hands-on training on GIS and Reviewed students work and assignments.

National Institute of Rural Development, Hyderabad, India

06/2014 - 07/2014

Intorn

• Developed land use land cover mapping, watershed analysis, change detection using satellite data.

EDUCATION

National University of Singapore, Singapore

08/2018 -07/2019

Graduate Diploma in Systems Analysis

• Relevant Coursework: Application Development Life Cycle, Project Management, java script, Python, HTML, CSS

CEPT University, Ahmedabad, India

2013 - 2015

Master of Science in Geomatics

- Master's thesis on Vulnerability Index Modeling sponsored by ISRO. The main objective of the study is to develop automated tool in ArcGIS using model builder.
- Some other academic projects included, Ward planning, analysis for TOZ area, Tool for Site Suitability Analysis, Designing Route Map for —Bike Racing Routes, Change detection etc.

Indian Institute of Remote Sensing, Dehradun, India

08/2014 - 03/2015

Remote sensing & GIS for Natural Resources Remote Sensing, GIS & Global Navigation Satellite System

- Relevant Coursework: Remote Sensing, Forest mapping & density assessment using RS data using visual & digital techniques
- Relevant Coursework: Basics of Remote Sensing, GIS and GNSS, Digital Image Analysis, Digital Image Processing

M.G Science Institute, Ahmedabad, India

2010 - 2013

Bachelor in Geology

Relevant Coursework: Concepts of Geologic materials, Structural geology, Petrology and Applied geology.

SKILLS & TOOLS

GIS ArcGIS, Q GIS, ERDAS IMAGINE, JOSM, Google Earth, PostgreSQL, Tableau

Programming HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, OpenLayers, Leaflet, NodeJS

Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Project

OTHER INTERESTS

I am a keen artist, regularly painting (glass) to a high standard to relax. I further regularly participate in a variety of cultural events, organizing and volunteering at numerous events.